(いの)今日中にオアシスに着かないと
水とかやばいんだからね。
We have to reach
the oasis sometime today,
(サクラ)えっ？ 水なら大サソリから
しぼったのがあるから➡
or else our provisions
will be in trouble!
少しくらい余裕あるわよ。
えっ!?
We have water that I extracted out
of that giant scorpion,
いくら余裕あるからって➡
so we can still get by!
中忍試験終わるまで
サソリの水だけなんてまっぴらよ。
Well, I refuse to "get by"
with scorpion water
(チョウジ)アッハッハッハ…。
for the rest of the Chunin Exam!
(コウジ)作戦どおりじゃないか。
(アメノ)別に作戦というほどの
ことでもありません。
It's just like you planned.
なっ！
I didn't account for this.
あなたたちは…。
You are...
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
The Yamanaka Clan: Secret Ninjutsu
あなたは…。
You are...
(アメノ)巻物を渡してください。
Please hand over your scroll.
そうすれば この先にある
オアシスの水をあげましょう。
Then we will allow you access to
the water in the oasis up ahead.
望むのなら治療の施しも。
And if you wish, medical treatment.
あんたなんかに
治療してもらう必要ないわ！
What?!
We don't need to be treated by you!
こっちには医療のスペシャリストが
いるんだから！
We have our own medical specialist!
いの…。
Ino...
うん！ それに➡
Yeah.
Besides, no one told us the oasis's
water belonged to anyone.
オアシスの水が誰かのものだなんて
聞いてないしね。
よく言ったわ チョウジ！
You tell 'em Choji!
サクラ あんたも言ってやんなさいよ。
Sakura, you tell 'em too!
治療はともかく
水が必要なのは確かよ。
We don't need treatment,
but we definitely need water.
戦う前から気落ちしてたら負けよ。
(サクラ)いの！
Hey, we'll lose even before we fight,
if you get weak like that!
(シシオ)んっ。
Ino!
砂陣 止威砂！
Sand Formation: Shisa!
キャ～！
いの！
Ino!
大丈夫？
Are you all right?
(シシオ)捨て駒だな。
So she was a pawn?
何の警戒もなく俺の
攻撃範囲内へと入ってくるとは。
Jumping within my range of attack
without taking any precautions...
フッ ダブル医療忍者のチームと聞いて
期待していたのですが➡
I heard this team had two Medical Ninja
and was curious...
医療忍者に必須の冷静な判断力が
その方にはありません。
But she doesn't have
the cool-headed judgment
required of a Medical Ninja.
残念ながら
見込み違いだったようです。
How disappointing that
my expectations were unwarranted.
(コウジ)と同時に
交渉決裂ってやつだ。
Which means... No more negotiating.
そのようね。
Seems that way.
気合いはもらった。
You just fired us up!
私とチョウジで
ここは突破してみせる。
Choji and I will break through this!
《医療水遁 ミズカマキリ》
Medical Water Style!
Water Praying Mantis!
安心してください。
Don't worry.
巻物さえ手に入れば
すぐに傷の治療にかかりますから。
Once we get your scroll,
I'll treat your wound.
《ただの水遁の刃なんかじゃない。
It's not an ordinary Water Style blade.
チャクラメスの鋭さを兼ね備えている。
It's as sharp as a Chakra Scalpel.
この人 強い》
She's very strong!
砂巌拳。
Saganken: Sand Stone Fist!
チッ 外したか。 んっ？
Damn! I missed!
《部分倍化の術！》
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
《この砂の拳…
大きさとパワーは僕と互角。
This sand fist... is equal to
my size and power...
でも…》
But...
《とんでもない硬さだ。
... it's ridiculously hard.
それに かなり重たいはず。
それを軽々と》
And it must be pretty heavy...
But he easily...
ハハッ どっちのパワーが上か
勝負しようぜ。
Let's see who's stronger!
《さすがです。
この連続攻撃を見切るなんて》
Amazing... To see through
successive attacks...
しまった…。
ハッ！
Damn it...
攻撃が単調だぜ。
Your attack is boring!
クッ…あいつ
自分の拳をブラインドに使いやがった。
He just took a blind swing!
苦戦してるようですね。
You seem to be having a hard time.
お前ほどじゃねえよ。
Not as hard as you.
２人とも 遊びすぎだ。
You two...
are fooling around too much.
チャクラを練り終えたか。
Did you finish infusing chakra?
いくぞ 偏光砂陣➡
Here I go!
Polarized Sand Formation.
熱砂迷彩！
Burning Sand Camouflage!
消えた…。
They disappeared!
うわっ！
チョウジ！
Choji!
他人の心配をしてる
場合ではありませんよ。
This is not the time...
to worry about the others.
ぐっ… わっ ぐぁ…。
見えぬ敵を相手に どう戦うかな。
Now, how will you fight
a foe you can't see?
チョウジ！ ２人バラバラに
離れていたら 不利！
Choji...
If we scatter,
we'll be at a disadvantage.
背中は預けたわよ。
う… うん！
You got my back?
U-Uh-huh!
うわぁ！
キャ～！
サクラ… チョウジ…。
Sakura... Choji...
((８時の方向 距離10。
At 8 o'clock, distance 10...
３時の方向 距離５。
At 3 o'clock, distance 5...
Two of them.
２頭…。
６時の方向 距離30。
At 6 o'clock, distance 30.
ダメ！ チャクラが乱れて わかんない！
It's no good!
My chakra's disrupted...
I can't tell!
はぁ…
ちょっと集中を乱されると➡
If my concentration
lapses even a little,
感知できなくなっちゃうなんて。
my Sensory Perception
doesn't work.
こんなんじゃ
実戦で使えないわよね。
I can't use this in actual battle...
ごめんね チョウジ。
中忍試験までには➡
I'm sorry, Choji.
I wanted to get this down
by the Chunin Exams, but...
間に合わせようと思ったんだけど。
ううん 感知できるってだけで
僕は すごいと思うけど。
It's okay.
The fact that you can even
do Sensory Perception
is amazing to me.
(シカマル)確かに 実戦じゃ
使えねえだろうな。
You can't use it in real battle,
that's for sure.
はぁ…。
(シカマル)だがよ
使えねえと思える駒ほど➡
However...
It's these little tricks
you think you can't use
(意外な奇襲が
成功したりするもんだぜ。 ヘッ！))
that somehow work in
an unexpected surprise attack.
まだ…。
Not yet...
終われない…。
... we can't let it end yet.
いや そろそろ終わりにしよう。
Nah... Let's finish things up here.
チョウジ 気をつけて！
Choji, watch out!
見えない敵に
どう気をつければいいの？
How do I watch out for
a foe I can't see?
自分で考えなさいよ。
Figure it out yourself!
６時の方向よ！
In the direction of six o'clock!
フンッ！
ハァ～ッ！
よっしゃ！ サンキュー シカマル！
All right!
Thank you, Shikamaru!
((見つけた！
移動中の３つのチャクラを感知した。
Found them! The three of them
are on the move.
I sense their chakra...
(いの)
敵がこっちに向かってるはずよ。
The enemy should be
heading this way.
あんた いつの間に感知なんて。
すごいじゃない！
Since when do you
have sensory powers?
That's amazing!
でしょ！
って言いたいとこなんだけど➡
"Right?!"
... is what I want to say,
まだ実戦では無理なのよね。
but in actual combat,
it's still difficult for me.
ある程度 落ち着いて
時間をとればできるんだけどね。
If I have the time
to concentrate I can do it.
(そうか 確かにそんな時間をくれる
敵なんていないしね))
I see...
Well, no enemy will give us
the luxury of time...
時間がなければ 奪えばいい。
If there's no time to spare,
you just have to steal it!
捨て駒のふりして
感知の時間を稼いだってわけよ。
I pretended to be a pawn
to buy time
and use Sensory Perception.
ただの騙し討ちのくせに
偉そうに。
Don't be so proud of yourself
for fooling us.
ほんとにやられたかと思って
心配したでしょ。
We thought he got you.
まあまあ。
Now, now...
いいのをもらっちまったぜ。
We're taking this.
この程度のダメージの回復に
時間はとらせはしません。
You can't buy time
for damage this small.
何よ!? どうなってんの!? あれ。
What? What the hell is going on?!
(シシオ)感知タイプがいたとはな。
I never expected
a Sensory Perception user
to be among you.
《完璧なカウンターだったはず》
That counter attack was
perfectly executed...
《倒せなかったこともだけど
あれほどのダメージを一瞬で…》
I'm shocked it didn't work...
But the speed with which
she undid the damage...
あらかじめチャクラを練り込んだ
医療水遁 ミズクラゲ。
I had kneaded chakra earlier
for this Medical Water Style
Water Jellyfish.
この自動回復がなければ…。
If it weren't for
this self-healing...
危ないところだったな。
We would have been in trouble.
コウジ シシオ ミズクラゲはもうありませんが
行けますか？
Kouji, Shishio...
I'm out of Water Jellyfish,
but can you still continue?
ああ 次は感知すらさせん。
Sure... This time,
I won't allow any sensing!
チョウジ サクラ すぐに感知を。
Choji, Sakura!
I'll track them with...
あっ！ これは感知妨害!?
Th-This is a sensory barrier?!
(シシオ)盲漠砂陣 濃偉砂！
Blinding Sand Formation: Noise!
(シシオ)お前には
もう仕事をさせない。
I won't let you sense us anymore!
うわぁ～！
いの！
Ino!
キャ～！
うぅ…。
(シシオ)アメノに感謝するんだな。
Be grateful to Ameno.
無駄に痛めつけると
あとで うるさいんだ。
She gets really upset
if I do too much damage.
(綱手)なんだい なんだい
その落ち着きのなさは。
What? What is it?
You're so antsy.
そんなに娘の中忍試験が
気がかりか？
Are you so worried about
your daughter's Chunin Exam?
(いのいち)面目ありません。
I won't make any excuses, but...
うちの子は 器用貧乏っていうか
八方美人なところがありまして➡
my daughter's what you call
a jack-of-all-trades
and master of none.
いつぞやは 秘伝忍術の修業を
サボって➡
Before I knew it,
she turned her back on
training in our Secret Jutsu...
医療忍術の修業なんて
始めやがって。
and took up
Medical Ninjutsu training.
あ… ツ 綱手様には大変ご迷惑を。
I mean... She's been such
a burden to you, Lady Tsunade...
気にするな。 それにな➡
Don't worry about it.
Besides, I don't intend to
make her a Medical Ninja.
私は医療忍者を
育てたつもりはないんだ。
えっ？
Huh?
まっ いずれ役に立てばとな。
I just thought it would come
in handy someday.
貴重な秘伝忍術の修業を
止めてまで行ったのだからな。
Since she skipped out training
for the Secret Jutsu
to come learn under me...
《相手が感知できなきゃ
心転身は使えない。
If I can't sense them,
I can't get into
Mind Transfer mode.
なら せめて
心伝身で２人と連絡を》
So I'll contact those two
with Mind Transmission...
《いの : サクラ チョウジ 聞こえる？》
Sakura, Choji... Can you hear me?
き 聞こえるよ。
I-I hear you.
いの なんとか
敵を感知できないの？
Ino! Can you do something
to sense the enemy?!
感知は妨害されてる。
My Sensory Perception
is being blocked.
でも敵の攻撃には
法則があると思う。
But... I think the enemy's attack
follows a pattern.
そんなこと
とっくにわかってる！
That's pretty obvious!
あっ。
(チョウジ)ぐわっ。
(サクラ)敵は死角から攻撃してくる。
The enemy attacks
from your blind side.
今みたいに 私からは
チョウジの相手が一瞬 見えても➡
Like just now,
I can see Choji's opponent.
見えてから伝えたんじゃ
間に合わない。
Except, it's already too late
when I see one coming.
やっぱり…。
I knew it...
((いのいち : 複数の人間が
同時に会話できる。
You can communicate with
several people at once.
これが心伝身の術だ。
This is
the Mind Transmission Jutsu.
《シカマル : 情報の伝達は
戦術の基本だ。
Transmission of intel is
a basic part of battle strategy.
それが敵に
バレねえってんなら➡
As long as the enemy
doesn't find out,
すげえ戦力になる》
it's a huge military asset.
《チョウジ : すごい術を
教わってんだね いの》
You learned an awesome jutsu, Ino!
《いの : ま まあね》
I-I guess...
便利な術ほどリスクが高い。
The more useful the jutsu,
the riskier it is.
心伝身の術もそうだ。
That goes for the Mind
Transmission Jutsu as well.
(いのいち)自分のレベルを見誤り➡
If you misjudge your level of skill
不用意に術のレベルを上げれば➡
and carelessly increase
the jutsu's intensity,
最悪の場合
死ぬことすらあるんだ。
in the worst case you could die.
(３人)あっ！
術のレベルを上げるってのは➡
By increasing the intensity,
do you mean
対象人数や範囲を広げる
ってことっすかね？
widening the scope or increasing
the number of people involved?
それによっちゃ戦略の立て方が
変わってくるんで。
I guess that would change
how we strategize...
うむ この心伝身の術には➡
Yes...
There are levels within
the Mind Transmission Jutsu
術者のレベルに応じた段階がある。
that correlates to the user's skill.
伝達速度 範囲 対象人数…。
Transmission speed, the scope,
the number of people
in the conversation...
それぞれ術者の
レベルに応じて変わってくる。
These change according
to the user's level.
そして術を極めたとき➡
And when truly mastered,
本当に大切なものを
伝えることができるようになる。
you are able to transmit
what is most precious.
本当に大切なもの？
What is most precious?
心伝身の術。
The Mind Transmission Jutsu...
すなわち わが身をもって
心を伝え合う術。
In other words, using your body
to communicate what is in someone's heart.
(いのいち)戦場で仲間の
思いの強さを知るとき➡
On the battlefield,
when you can feel the intensity of
your teammates thoughts for you...
(それが何よりの勇気となる))
that gives you more courage
than anything.
《いの : 今の私のレベルは➡
I've only scratched
the surface of this jutsu...
ほんの入り口程度。
もっと修業に
時間をかけていれば…。
If only I had spent
more time training...
医療忍術に費やした時間を➡
If only I had spent the time
I used training in Medical Ninjutsu,
遠回りせずに父さんとの
修業に使っていれば…》
training with Dad...
((綱手 : チャクラコントロールが
雑だから そうなる。
That happens because
your chakra control is too rough.
(もっと繊細かつ手際よく
チャクラコントロールしろ！))
Control your chakra more delicately!
綱手様…。
Lady Tsunade...
サクラ チョウジ 聞いて！
Sakura, Choji, listen up!
えっ？
そんなことできるの？
Huh?!
You can do that?!
できる できないじゃない
やるしかない！
It doesn't matter... I have to do it.
今の私よりも
もっと高みのレベルで。
I have to raise my level
much, much more.
心伝身の術！
Mind Transmission Jutsu!
《いの : サクラの心を
チョウジに届ける！》
Send Sakura's thoughts to Choji!
来たっ この心をチョウジに。
It worked!
Send these thoughts to Choji.
あっ！
やった！
I did it!
何か見えたけど
これじゃ間に合わないよ。
I saw something, but at this rate,
I won't make it in time.
中継してたら時間がかかりすぎる。
Transmitting takes too long.
サクラの心を直接チョウジに届けないと。
I have to send Sakura's thoughts
straight to Choji.
諦めない！
I won't give up! More! More!
もっともっと
心伝身のレベルを上げる！
I will raise the level of
my Mind Transmission!
《もっと もっと➡
More... more...
もっと… もっと！》
More... more!
(チョウジ)あっ！
《今度は 僕の心を！》
My thoughts this time!
はっ！
しゃんなろ～！
Cha...
な… なぜだ…。
How?
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
貴様… まさか!?
How could you... Impossible!
勝負を決めたのは
強い思いの力よ。
Intense feelings decided
the outcome of this fight.
いの まだやれる？
Ino, are you still up to it?
当たり前でしょ！
Of course!
じゃ さっさと片づけちゃうよ！
ええ！
Then let's finish this.
Right.
ちょ ちょい待った…。
W-Wait!
(３人)問答無用！
– No excuses!
う… うう… うわ～!!
はい これで大丈夫です。
All right, that should do it.
中忍試験中で 今は
敵チームなのに ありがとうね。
We're in the middle of
the Chunin Exams
and we're on opposite sides,
so thank you.
医療くノ一ですから
当然の行いです。
I'm a Medical Kunoichi.
This is what we do.
ナッハハハ。 これだから➡
Is it any wonder guys
love Medical Kunoichi?!
医療くノ一に
萌えない男はいない！
何また くだらないこと
言ってんのよ！
Why are you saying
that nonsense again?!
(チョウジ)萌え萌え。
Moe, moe!
じゃあ 出発しましょう。
Well, let's get going.
But are you sure about this?
でも 本当にいいんですか？
いいのよ。 私たちは
巻物 揃ってるんだから。
Yes. We have our scrolls.
Just the water itself is appreciated.
水だけもらえればね。
ですが…。
But...
本当の完敗ってやつだな…。
Talk about complete defeat...
だが必ず 巻物揃えて
三次試験でリベンジだ。
Well, we'll get both scrolls and
get our revenge in the Third Exam.
Yup. I don't consider this
a victory either.
うん。 僕も
勝ったつもりなんてないから➡
次で決着をつけようね。
So let's settle it next time we meet.
あなたの感知妨害には
苦戦させられたわ。
The barrier you put up against
my Sensory Perception was really tough.
いえ あなたのスキルを➡
No, we underestimated your skill.
甘くみてしまった
僕たちの負けです。
That was our downfall.
そうよ！ あんた
いつの間に あんなことが➡
He's right!
When did you learn
to do that anyway?!
できるようになったのよ？
え!? そうね…。
Huh? Well...
フッフフ…。
「能ある鷹は爪隠す」ってやつ？
What's the saying?
"He who knows, speaks least."
私も綱手様の
弟子の一人だってとこ➡
I just wanted to prove that
I'm Lady Tsunade's apprentice too.
見せてやったまでよ！
(チョウジ)いいこと 言った！
Well said!
じゃあ そろそろ 僕らはこっちへ。
Anyway, we'll be going this way.
私たちはこっちへ。
And we'll go this way.
SENSORY PERCEPTION DIVISION
山中一族の秘伝忍術には
医療忍術の心得である➡
Extreme delicacy is
required to perform
the Secret Ninjutsu of
the Yamanaka Clan.
I have no doubt that the chakra control
skill required in Medical Ninjutsu
繊細なチャクラコントロールが
役に立つだろう。
will come in handy.
綱手様…。
Lady Tsunade...!
It may seem she's taking a detour,
but she's learning what she must.
あいつは遠回りしているようで➡
吸収すべきことは
ちゃんと学んでいる。
それは 父親であるお前が➡
And you, as her father must
be well aware of that.
いちばん わかってるだろうがな。
《お前はいずれ
俺を超え… いや➡
In time, you will surpass me...
山中一族で 一番の忍になると➡
In fact, I have faith that
you will become
the foremost shinobi
of the Yamanaka Clan!
俺は信じてるぞ！》
ちょっと手強い敵だったね。
Those guys were pretty formidable.
Who knows what would have
happened if you weren't here Ino.
いのがいなかったら
今ごろどうなってたか…。
そんなことないわ。
Don't say that. You two bought
me time, that's why.
２人が時間稼ぎしてくれたから。
２人の頑張りがなければ
今ごろ どうなっていたか…。
If you two didn't give it your all,
who knows...?
《父さん ごめん。
修業サボっちゃって…。
I'm sorry, Dad, for skipping out
on my training.
Please forgive me, Lady Tsunade...
綱手様 すみません。
医療忍術の修業が➡
For thinking that Medical Ninjutsu
was an easy way out.
遠回りだったなんて思って。
綱手様との修業が
医療忍術の修業が➡
Your guidance and training
in Medical Ninjutsu helped me to grow.
私を成長させてくれたんですね。
冷静な判断 繊細なチャクラコントロール。
Calm decision-making,
delicate chakra control...
すべては 自分の
進むべき場所に向かって！》
Everything is pushing me in
the direction that I'm destined to go.
All right, let's do our best
and reach our goal!
さあ 頑張ってゴールするわよ！
うん！
Okay.
hitori ja nai yo
You're not alone
osoreru mono nante nai kara
There's nothing to be afraid of
ikou saa me o ake te
Let's go, now open your eyes
butsukatte ita
I was crashing into you
hontou wa oitsuki taku te
I just wanted to catch up so badly
kizutsuke atte
We hurt one another
tsunagi tomeru kizuna hoshiku te
I just wanted a bond to connect me to you
"gomen" wasure nai de
"I'm sorry" Don't forget
shinji te matte te
Trust in me and wait
mukae ni ikun da
I'll come for you
yuuki no tomoshibi terashidase yowa sa o
The light of courage, reveal our weaknesses
kizu datte itami datte wakeae ba heiki da
If we share our wounds and pain, we'll be fine
kimi no senaka osu musun da yakusoku
This is the promise I made you push you forward
itsu datte hanare tatte
No matter when, even if we're apart
shinjirareru kizuna wa mune ni nemutteru
The bond I believe in rests in my heart
What? A doll? An enemy?
< きょうから15代目>
Sakura! How are you doing physically?
You guys made it possible
for me to rest so I'm okay.
<旬の小鉢が大好きな豆助>
He's a puppet user!
Ino, he's coming this way!
If our enemy is a puppet user,
if we get the jutsu user then we'll...
Sakura, use my body!
豆助 きょうは今が旬の
あれを使った小鉢よ
Leave it to me!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Cursed Puppet"
This guy's dangerous!
< その小鉢とは？>